(Let it go.)
=Revenge From A Wife=
=Episode 15=
Su Cao.
You wretch!
Help!
Someone, help!
(Once this palace job is done)
(and I get paid,)
(I'll buy you a fur collar.)
(If others can have one,)
(so can you.)
How dare a lowly grass weaver
talk back to Her Highness?
What are you waiting for?
Please show mercy, Your Highness!
(Let it go.)
I pay my respects, Your Highness.
You recognize me?
His Majesty once mentioned
your retreat at West Buddhist Hall
and that you prefer not to be disturbed.
So you're Noble Lady Hui,
His Majesty's new consort.
Yes.
At this hour,
you're not at Jiyun Pavilion,
but here in a forbidden area.
I meant to
go see Concubine Yu,
but I'm new to the palace
and don't know my way around.
I must have taken a wrong turn.
You smell of sulfur
from Mufang Pool.
And your sleeve is wet.
You're very observant, Your Highness.
I was in a hurry just now.
There was water on the stone steps,
and I accidentally got my sleeve wet.
As for the sulfur smell,
can't Your Highness
smell it here too?
I've been on retreat here for two weeks.
It's never been this strong.
If you suspect I trespassed here,
you can have it investigated.
However,
Mufang Pool was the late Empress's.
If my wrong turn
brings the guards here to search,
and word reaches His Majesty,
it may reopen old wounds.
You seem
to understand the Emperor quite well.
I wouldn't claim that.
His Majesty's devotion
is known throughout the palace.
Since he has shown me such favor,
naturally, I should think of him more.
Are you thinking of His Majesty,
or of yourself?
In the palace,
if you don't think of yourself,
you won't last long.
I just want to live a little longer.
But from the look in your eyes just now,
you didn't seem afraid to die.
It seemed more like
you were afraid I'd ruin your plans.
If Your Highness truly wanted me dead,
your first words
would've been to summon the guards,
not to ask why I was here.
You're testing me.
I wouldn't dare.
I just don't think
you're heartless.
You've only met me once.
How could you know
I'm not heartless?
You may seem withdrawn from the world,
but you see more clearly than anyone.
Perhaps too clearly.
That's why you can't bear to act.
Others may call that weakness.
But I think
it's compassion.
Noble Lady Hui.
His Majesty says
you resemble the late Empress.
Seeing you now,
perhaps he wasn't entirely wrong.
I wouldn't dare compare myself to her.
Of course you could never match her.
Roujia...
never lied.
Search carefully.
Someone's there.
Greetings, Your Highness.
We're conducting a routine patrol
of the restricted Mufang Pool area.
May I ask if you've seen
anyone suspicious?
I've been on retreat here quite a while.
I haven't seen anyone suspicious.
In that case,
I'll take my leave.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Why did you
really come to the palace?
(Noble Lady Hui.)
♪Sunset fades beyond the lonely city♪
♪Dusk snow paints the green hills♪
♪A lone rider storms the old pass♪
♪Drunk, I gaze by lamplight♪
♪Old friends have all drifted away♪
♪My broken sword rusts, as do I♪
♪Jackdaws cry into the night♪
♪Half a banner snaps in the wind♪
♪In dreams, I return to the camps♪
♪Moonlight chills my armor♪
♪Life is a dream through many winters♪
♪I gaze beyond the edge of the world♪
♪Parting sorrow spills across the moon♪
♪The moon and wind mean nothing now♪
♪History turns to ash before ink dries♪
♪Who plays the zither
and sighs at the pavilion?♪
♪The past has faded away♪